http://www.wellcome.ac.uk/about-us/governance/privacy-and-terms#cookies

Cookies
Wellcome uses cookies to improve your experience. Find out more about cookies.
Manage preferences
Accept and close
Skip to main content
Privacy and terms
Terms of use including privacy, cookies and disclaimer.
Privacy
Wellcome is committed to safeguarding your personal information in accordance with data protection law.
The
Wellcome Privacy Statement [PDF 313KB] explains how, and on what legal basis, we collect, store, and use personal information about you as:
a visitor to Wellcome Collection, our offices and our websitesan applicant for a job at Wellcomea participant in any of our eventsa lender or donor to, or recipient of loan items from, Wellcome Collectionor when you otherwise choose to interact with us.
It also explains how we use personal information in Wellcome Collection for the purpose of archiving in the public interest.
Information on how we collect, store and use personal information in connection with grant-making is set out in our
Wellcome Grants Privacy and Confidentiality Statement [PDF 296KB].
Cookies
Last updated 27th September 2017
Like most organisations, Wellcome uses cookies to capture information about our websites’ users. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we save to your computer or device if you agree.
Cookies allow us to recognise and count your visits, and to see how you move around our sites while you are using them. This helps us to provide you with a good experience while you browse and to improve the way our sites work, for example by making sure you can find what you need.
Cookies are also set when you:
click on social networking buttons in our pageswatch videosregister for servicestake part in surveys and other activities.
Third-party cookies
As well as the cookies we set, we may use third party cookies and other similar technologies set by other websites when you visit them to help us to understand some simple information about the age, location and interests of the people who visit our sites. Third parties may use these technologies to collect or recieve information from our website and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and to target adverts.
We only ever use this information in aggregate, and never associate it with any personal information that might identify you.
You can opt out of being tracked by cookies set by third parties by using the Google ad preferences page or the opt-out tool.
You can also get more information from Google or the Your Online Choices website.
You can opt out of being tracked and the collection and use of information for Facebook ad targeting in your ad settings page on Facebook. You can also get more information from Facebook on their use of cookies and advertising policies.
You can opt out of tracking from all participating companies through the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance 'Your Online Choices' site. In the UK, click on the 'Your ad choices' menu option.
By continuing to use our sites and by using video and social media functionality, you consent to the relevant cookies being set on your device.
For general information about cookies, and how to control and disable them, please visit www.allaboutcookies.orgCookies we use on our sites by type
Across our sites we may make use of Flash files, which present information, allow integration with third parties (such as YouTube) and can offer a richer online experience. We have strived to identify any Flash elements that are likely to set cookies but, at this point in time, we cannot guarantee the status of every Flash file. Adobe offers a tool to monitor and remove Flash cookies.
We use Google Analytics, Google Analytics demographics and interest reporting, and integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and identifiers. Google Analytics is a tool that helps website and app owners to understand how their visitors behave. It uses a set of cookies to collect information and report website usage statistics without personally identifying individual visitors to Google. It also uses some cookies set by other websites to help us understand more about our sites’ visitors.
We use web beacons like Facebook Pixel to understand what users of our site do after clicking a link in an email that we’ve sent to a list of subscribers, or clicking on an advert we’ve placed on Facebook. This information helps us to improve the content we make, reach people who are interested in our work with our advertising and social activity, and measure how effective our advertising and newsletters are, without personally identifying individual site visitors, newsletter subscribers or Facebook users.
The following table is a list of the cookies we use, why we use them, and on which of our sites.
Details of cookie usage on Wellcome sites
NamePurposeThird PartyDuration__zlcstoreThis cookie is necessary for the chat-box function on the website to function.Yes20 daysCookieConsentStores the user's cookie consent state for the current domainNo1 yearhas_jsRegisters whether or not the user has activated JavaScript in the browser.NosessionZD-suidUnique id that identifies the user's session.No20 days__cfduidUsed by the content network, Cloudflare, to identify trusted web traffic.Yes1 year__cfruidThis cookie is a part of the services provided by Cloudflare - Including load-balancing, deliverance of website content and serving DNS connection for website operators.Yessession__cfduidUsed by the content network, Cloudflare, to identify trusted web traffic.Yes1 yearZD-storeRegisters whether the self-service-assistant Zendesk Answer Bot has been displayed to the website user.No20 dayscollectUsed to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor's device and behavior. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.Yessession_gaRegisters a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.No2 years_gatUsed by Google Analytics to throttle request rateNo1 day_gidRegisters a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.No1 day_hjidSets a unique ID for the session. This allows the website to obtain data on visitor behaviour for statistical purposes.No1 year_hjidSets a unique ID for the session. This allows the website to obtain data on visitor behaviour for statistical purposes.No20 dayshjViewportIdSets a unique ID for the session. This allows the website to obtain data on visitor behaviour for statistical purposes.NosessionZD-buidUnique id that identifies the user on recurring visits.No20 daysZD-currentTimeRegisters the date and time for the user's latest visit to the website.NosessionAWSALBRegisters which server-cluster is serving the visitor. This is used in context with load balancing, in order to optimize user experience.Yes6 daysIDEUsed by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user's actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser's ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.Yes1 yeartest_cookieUsed to check if the user's browser supports cookies.Yes1 dayfrUsed by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.Yes3 monthstrUsed by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.Yessessionrc::cThis cookie is used to distinguish between humans and bots.Yessession__zlcmidPreserves users states across page requests.No1 year_fbpUsed by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.No3 months_gaexpThis cookie is used by Google Analytics to determine if the visitor is involved in their marketing experiments.No3 months_hjIncludedInSampleDetermines if the user's navigation should be registered in a certain statistical place holder.NosessionGPSRegisters a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.Yes1 dayPREFRegisters a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.Yes1 yearVISITOR_INFO1_LIVETries to estimate the users' bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.Yes6 monthsYSCRegisters a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.Yessessionyt-remote-cast-installedStores the user's video player preferences using embedded YouTube videoYessessionyt-remote-connected-devicesStores the user's video player preferences using embedded YouTube videoYes20 daysyt-remote-device-idStores the user's video player preferences using embedded YouTube videoYes20 daysyt-remote-fast-check-periodStores the user's video player preferences using embedded YouTube videoYessessionyt-remote-session-appStores the user's video player preferences using embedded YouTube videoYessessionyt-remote-session-nameStores the user's video player preferences using embedded YouTube videoYessession_gaexp_rc No1 day
Disclaimer
The material contained in the Wellcome Trust website is provided for general purposes only. Although we endeavour to ensure that the content is accurate and up to date, the Wellcome Trust accepts no responsibility for loss arising from reliance on information contained in this site or other sites that may be linked to from our site from time to time.
Unless otherwise stated, all content on the site is © The Wellcome Trust and is licensed under Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 UK.
This means that you are free to share the content by copying, distributing and transmitting it, but please attribute it to the Wellcome Trust and provide a link to its website https://wellcome.org. For any reuse or distribution, you must make these licence terms clear to others.
